

Colin J. Christoph

- Maricopa, AZ 85139 (847) 902-0610
- colinchristoph27@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Detail-oriented, organized and meticulous professional. Works at fast pace to meet tight deadlines. Enthusiastic team player ready to contribute to company success. I have a very unique experience that makes me as well rounded as you can be and I think that will make me a better software engineer/developer.

PORTFOLIO

https://colinc27.github.io/ColinsReactPortfolio/

SKILLS

- Customer and quality-focused
- Data Analysis
- Mathematically inclined
- Complex problem solver
- Application Design and Development
- Software Components and Libraries

- Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)
- Full-stack Development
- Javascript, CSS, HTML
- MERN stack development
- Back-end: MongoDB, SQL, NO SQL
- JS Frameworks: React

WORK HISTORY

PRESIDENT'S CLUB CLOSING SPECIALIST

11/2020 to 05/2022

Quicken Loans | Phoenix, AZ

- Coordinated with sellers, buyers, escrow agents and real estate agents to complete loan submissions and scheduled closing dates.
- Balanced closing disclosures, fixed post-closing issues, and completed some UW tasks
- Produced and submitted completed loan packages to title and escrow professionals.
- Leveraged this experience to develop my communication, business, and sales skills
- Constantly received achieves/exceeds expectations in monthly review and was promoted twice for excellent communication skills and being a subject matter expert to our team.

PRODUCTION/MANUFACTURING ENGINEER

09/2018 to 11/2020

Swiss Precision Machining | Wheeling, IL

- Identified problems and specific resolutions to fix defective, damaged or malfunctioning parts, assemblies, equipment and systems.
- Selected manufacturing methods, fabrication and operations to develop and coordinate production.

- Led the 3D printing design team and was the best engineering resource for Solidworks and ESPRIT
- Created 100's of programs sometimes 50K lines of code long
- Managed manufacturing projects and program services to handle engineering and project metrics.

TECHNICAL MARKETING ENGINEER

06/2018 to 09/2018

Wieland Thermal Solutions | Wheeling, IL

- Provided technical expertise to customers looking to design a new product
- Wrote documents and created presentations sharing technical details of products, technologies and solutions.
- Created engineering drawings for new customer products
- Performed root cause analysis to determine quality issues occurring on the manufacturing line

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science | Mechanical Engineering

05/2018

Iowa State University, Ames, IA

- Dean's List Every Semester
- Honoree of Tau Beta Pi Scholarship
- 3.66 GPA
- Magna cum laude graduate
- Study Abroad: Ireland, Fluid Mechanics
- Sigma Pi Fraternity Member

CERTIFICATIONS

Michigan State University-Coding Bootcamp Graduate